(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-05T21:41:08.719551",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Yeah
One, two, check, check
Yo, ah
We show, clown we show
Uh, haha
Yeah, haha
Come on, come on, yo, uh
No te quejes
Don't complain
Kj, ACO, Zeebra, yeah
Hot show, Otora go I show, come on
I got feel...
Come on, yeah, uh-huh, 行くぞ, yo
Come on, yeah, uh-huh, let's go, yo
Turn up radio そう今日も聞こえるよ
Turn up the radio, yeah, I can hear it today too
風に揺られ流れるStereo
The stereo sways in the wind
肩で刻む軽快なRhythm
Bobbing my shoulders to the buoyant rhythm
想いをのっけて届けるよRhyme
Riding my feelings on the rhyme to deliver them
よく晴れた空の真下
Right under the clear blue sky,
僕らは遥かな未来目指しました
we set our sights on the distant future.
Master key 握り締め出発
Gripping the master key tight, we set off,
雑踏の中Kick down一発
kicking into gear through the hustle and bustle.
今想う闘いの日々
Looking back now on those days of struggle,
感謝すごとに溢れ出す慈悲
compassion overflows with every word of thanks.
しのぎを削ったあの攻防戦
That fierce battle where we gave our all,
今なお続くここは最前線
still continues today—this is the front line.
父から得た揺るぎ無い誇り
The unwavering pride I received from my father,
母がくれた大きないたわり
the immense compassion my mother gave me,
キミにもらう温かいぬくもり
the gentle warmth I get from you,
明日への糧に生き抜くために
become the fuel to survive into tomorrow.
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when the sky's gray
You make me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yo
俺は東京生まれHIP HOP育ち
Born in Tokyo, raised on hip-hop
悪そうな奴は大体友達
Most bad-looking guys are my friends
悪そうな奴と大体同じ
Pretty much the same as those bad-looking guys
裏の道歩き見てきたこの街
Walking the backstreets, watching this city
渋谷 六本木 そう思春期も早々に
Shibuya, Roppongi, yeah, early in my youth
これにぞっこんに
Totally fell in love with this
カバンなら置き放してきた高校に
Left my bag behind at high school
マジ親に迷惑かけた本当に
Really caused a lot of trouble for my parents
だが時は経ち 今じゃ雑誌のカヴァー
But time passed, and now I'm on magazine covers
そこらじゅうで幅利かす DON DADA
Throwing my weight around everywhere, don dada
マイク掴んだらマジでNo.1
Once I grab the mic, I'm seriously number one
東京代表トップランカーだ
Representing Tokyo as a top ranker
そう この地この国に生を授かり
Yeah, given life in this land, this country
Jahに無敵のマイク預かり
Entrusted with an invincible mic by Jah
仲間たち 親たち ファンたちに今日も
To my crew, my parents, and my fans, today too
感謝して進む荒れたオフロード
Giving thanks as I push through this rough off-road
I got sound. I got feel. I got beautiful days
I got song. I got love. I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You make me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yo, mic check 1, 2, uh
日出ずる国に僕ら生まれ育ち
Born and raised in the land of the rising sun
今こうして踏みしめる大地
Now standing firm upon this earth
常に開く新しいPage
Always turning a brand new page
旅に出ようそれぞれのStage
Let's set off on a journey to our own stage
ここに綴る喜びと感謝
Spanning joy and gratitude right here
共に奏でる真の理解者
True comrades playing together in harmony
つつみ隠さず時代を描写
Depicting the times without hiding a thing
Pressureはねのけて乱反射
Shrugging off pressure with a wild reflection
注ぎ込もう溢れ出す感情
Let's pour in these overflowing feelings
いつの日にも絶やさない愛情
An affection that never fades on any day
ひるむことなく飛び込む戦場
Diving into the battlefield without flinching
枯れることなく咲く百合の紋章
The lily emblem blooming without ever wilting
やさしい風ぬける昼下がり
A gentle breeze blowing through the early afternoon
虹がのぞいたこんな雨上がり
A rainbow peeking through after the rain
陽の光映した水たまり
Puddles reflecting the sunlight
日々の歓びここに賛美
Giving praise right here to the joys of every day
この胸の高鳴りを
This fluttering in my chest...
歌にのせて
...riding on a song
日々ここにあるもの
Everything that exists right here, day by day...
この手に感じて
...feeling it in these hands
I got sound. I got feel. I got beautiful days
I got song. I got love. I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You make me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yo SEAMO, ZEEBRA coming through, yeah
共に進もう
Let's advance together
あーーーっ！
Aaah!
だっ
Oof!
ルパン
Lupin
ル、ル、ルパン
Lu-Lu-Lupin
ルパン！
Lupin!
ルパン三世
[Lupin the Third]
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
[Lupin The Fire]
Let me show you my everything 夢のこのファンタジー見てな
Let me show you my everything, behold this dreamy fantasy
今こそ走る時なんだ (It's show time)
Now is the time to run (It's show time)
そこで見ててよ ワンマンショー これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
Watch from right there, my one-man show! A trial like this isn't enough!
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない I steal your heart
What I want isn't material things, I steal your heart
Listen! Party people! 僕は人生駆け上がる猛スピード
Listen! Party people! I rush up through life at breakneck speed
まるでスキーの直滑降 核弾頭 決めたことには頑固
Like a downhill ski run, a nuclear warhead, stubborn about what I decide
ゆっくり生きる術なんて知らない ここはステージ遠慮は要らない
Don't know how to take life slow, this is the stage, no holding back
やることはやりますわ 高みの山目指せ
I'll get done what needs to be done, aim for the mountain peak!
Put your hands up in the air!
僕を見つめる君はセクシー 甘くとろけるまるでチェルシー
Gazing at me, you're so sexy, meltingly sweet just like Chelsea
手櫛で髪掻きあげる様 僕にとっての女王様
Raking fingers through your hair, you're like a queen to me
そんなあなたを今夜抱きしめる
I'll embrace you tonight,
And 熱い唇をいただく
and take your hot lips.
そして何よりも欲しいのよ あなたの心 狂おしいほど
And more than anything, I want your heart to a maddening degree.
It's a party night Dancin' with us Everybody don't stop dance
Let's go just do it!
茨の道だろうが 凍てつく夜だろうが
Whether it's a thorny path or a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ 君と二人で
the impossible becomes possible when I'm with you.
ルパン・ザ・サード
Lupin the Third!
だから そう だから 誰も手にした事ないお宝貰う
That's why, yes, that's why I'll take the treasure nobody has ever claimed.
狙った獲物は逃がさない それがなんだ大泥棒
I won't let my prey escape; after all, I'm a master thief.
先の先まで計算だって 瞬時にひらめく名案
Calculating far ahead, a brilliant scheme flashes in an instant.
そして「あっ」と思ったらもう居ない
And once you think "Ah!", I'm already gone.
もはや芸術 盗みの美学
It's practically art, the aesthetics of theft.
Put your hands up in the air!
Let me show you my everything 夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Let me show you my everything, behold this fantasy of a dream.
今こそ走る時なんだ (It's show time)
Now is the time to run (It's show time).
そこで見ててよ ワンマンショー これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
Watch me right there in my one-man show, trials like this aren't nearly enough.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない I steal your heart
What I want isn't material things, I steal your heart.
待て待て！絶対に逃がさん！
Wait, wait! I definitely won't let you get away!
無駄な抵抗はやめて大人しく縄につけ！ルパン！逃がさんぞ！
Stop resisting uselessly and surrender quietly! Lupin! You won't get away!
誰かが居ないと張り合いない 相手が居てこそ間違いない
Without someone around, there's no rivalry; having an opponent makes it all real.
身近にゃ素敵なライバル 競い合い互いにハイになる
With wonderful rivals nearby, competing together gets us hyped.
ファイナルステージだ天王山 お前と勝負の演奏さ
It's the final stage, the deciding battle, playing a duel of tunes with you.
マジで今夜はサシで どっちが勝っても文句はナシで
Seriously, going head-to-head tonight, no complaints no matter who wins!
Put your hands up in the air!
ワルサー使いこなす僕はワルさ 曲がったこと嫌いプラスアルファ
Wielding my Walther, I'm bad to the bone, plus I despise crooked ways.
ラップマスター ジェダイも目じゃない
A rap master, even the Jedi don't stand a chance.
しかし可愛い女にも目が無い
Yet I also can't resist cute girls.
Oh baby それは演技? or 本気? 僕は君に一本気
Oh baby, is that an act or for real? I'm totally devoted to you.
一本道走り続けます 空へ飛ばす今日から明日
I'll keep running down this straight road, taking off into the sky from today to tomorrow.
It's a party night Dancin' with us Everybody don't stop dance
Let's go just do it!
茨の道だろうが 凍てつく夜だろうが
Whether it's a thorny path or a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ 君と二人で
the impossible becomes possible when I'm with you.
ルパン・ザ・サード
Lupin the Third!
Let me show you my everything 夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Let me show you my everything, behold this fantasy of a dream.
今こそ走る時なんだ (It's show time)
Now is the time to run (It's show time).
そこで見ててよ ワンマンショー これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
Watch me right there in my one-man show, trials like this aren't nearly enough.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない あんたのハート
What I want isn't material things, it's your heart.
愛すべき仲間や家族がいる
I have precious friends and family I love,
信念やプライドを曲げずに貫くべし！
and I must uphold my convictions and pride without bending!
ルパン・ザ・サード
Lupin the Third!
Let me show you my everything
眩しい眼差しをうけて 君のために今日を捨てるよ
basking in that dazzling gaze, I'll cast today aside for you.
(It's show time)
世界で一人の最愛の君自身に気持ち伝えたいよ
I want to convey my feelings to you yourself, my one and only dearest in the world.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない あなたのハート
What I want isn't material things, it's your heart.
普段はとぼけた三枚目 やるときゃ誰より真剣で
Usually playing the goofy fool, but when it's time, more serious than anyone,
頼りになるいざという時 こうなりたい誰もが見ても素敵
reliable when push comes to shove, someone anyone looks at and finds cool.
知性備えたスーパーマン
A Superman endowed with intellect,
横にはお決まりスーパーウーマン
with the usual Superwoman by his side.
残り二小節 ラストスパート
Two bars left, the final spurt,
憧れの男 Lupin The Third
the man everyone admires: Lupin the Third!
Yeah!
獲物は確かにいただいたぜ
I've definitely claimed the prize!
はい！
Alright!
ということで、『Great Days』と『ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー』を2曲続けて聴いていただきましたー！
And with that, you just heard two songs back-to-back: "Great Days" and "Lupin the Fire"!
『Great Days』はですね、えっと、男性2人と女性1人の、えっと、曲なんですけど、
For "Great Days," well, it's originally a song by two men and one woman,
女性のところはね、絶対AZKiちゃんがいいということでAZKiちゃん、
but for the female part, I really wanted AZKi-chan, so I got AZKi-chan,
で、ラップパートは、もうノエルちゃんの顔しか浮かばなかったので、ノエルちゃんにお願いしました。
and for the rap part, only Noel-chan came to mind, so I asked Noel-chan.
2人ともありがとー！
Thank you so much, both of you!
でね、ルパンの映像が流れてみんなびっくりしたんじゃない？ころねもびっくりした！
And the Lupin footage played, so weren't you all surprised? Korone was surprised too!
で、今日のハッシュタグは、もうね、7周年だって！すごいよね！
And today's hashtag—it's already the 7th anniversary! Isn't that amazing?
この上のハッシュタグ「#戌神ころね7周年」で、ぜひいっぱいつぶやいてくださーい！
Please tweet a ton using the hashtag above: "#InugamiKorone7thAnniversary"!
スクショも大丈夫だよー。
Taking screenshots is totally fine too!
ねえ、ここのステージ、なんか今日は違った感じだけど、
Hey, this stage feels a bit different today,
ここはどこなんでしょうか？
but where do you think this is?
どこー？
Where is it?
イヌバレー！
Inu Valley!
素敵！今日はイヌバレーから、え、全てお送りしますので、よろしくお願いします！
Wonderful! Everything is being brought to you from Inu Valley today, so please enjoy!
って思ったんだけどさ、なんか画面小さくない？って思ったよね、リスナーさんね？
That being said, didn't you listeners feel like the screen is kind of narrow?
ころねもちょっとそう思ったので、
Korone thought so too,
ちょっとね…あ、ちょっと待って！なんか字が寄ってる！字が寄ってる！やめて！
so let's... Ah, wait a minute! The borders are closing in! They're closing in! Stop!
やばいやばい！カイブツになっちゃうよ、これ！
Oh no, oh no! I'm gonna turn into Kaibutsu like this!
ちょっと押して、今は令和なのでね、画面を広く使いたいので、あっち行け！
Let's push them back. We're in the Reiwa era now, so I want widescreen! Go over there!
もうちょいあっち行け！
Go over there a bit more!
もうちょい！
A bit more!
オッケオッケオッケ！
Okay, okay, okay!
こっちは？
What about this side?
あっち行け！
Go over there!
え、そんなにころねと居たいの？おいで？
Wait, do you want to be with Korone that badly? Come here?
本当に来んじゃねえよ！本当に来んな！あっち行け！
Don't actually come over here! Don't really come! Go away!
よー、早くー！
Hey, hurry up!
行った？
Are they gone?
行ったね。何だったんだろうね？ということで...
They're gone. I wonder what that was? Anyway...
おっ、なんか...
Oh, something...
なんか落ちてきたよ。
Something fell down.
花びらかな、これ。あっちから降ってきた？
Is this a petal? Did it fall from over there?
ちょっと行ってみよう！
Let's go check it out!
さくら
作詞・作曲: ケツメイシ
[Song: Sakura / Lyrics & Music: Ketsumeishi]
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amidst the fluttering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories
君の声が戻ってくる
and your voice come flooding back.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind that never ceases,
あの頃のままで
just like it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
When you parted your hair dancing in the wind,
淡い香り戻ってくる
that faint scent comes flooding back.
二人約束した
Just like when we made our promise,
あの頃のままで
just like it was back then.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira
さくら散りだす 思い出す 意味なく 灯り出す あの頃また気になる
Sakura starts scattering, memories surface, lit up without reason, I find myself longing for back then again.
変わらない香り 景色 風 違うのは君がいないだけ
The unchanging scent, scenery, and wind; the only difference is that you aren't here.
ここに立つと甦る こみ上げる記憶 読み返す
Standing here brings it all back; memories welling up, I replay them in my mind.
春風に舞う長い髪 たわいないことでまた騒いだり
Your long hair fluttering in the spring breeze, laughing over silly little things,
さくら木の真下 語り明かした 思い出は俺輝いた証だ
talking the night away under the cherry blossom tree; those memories are proof I truly shone.
さくら散る頃 出会い別れ それでも ここまで変わらぬままで
When the cherry blossoms fall, we meet and part, yet it stays unchanged all the way here.
咲かした芽 君離した手 いつしか別れ 交わしたね
The buds bloomed, we let go of our hands, and before long exchanged goodbyes.
さくら舞う季節に取り戻す あの頃そして君呼び起こす
In the season when cherry blossoms flutter, I'll take back those days and awaken thoughts of you.
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Petals dance and fall, memories come dancing back.
気付けばまたこの季節で 君との想い出に誘われ
Before I know it, this season is here again, lured by memories of you,
心の扉叩いた でも手をすり抜けた花びら
I knocked on the door of my heart, but the petals slipped right through my fingers.
初めて分かった 俺若かった この場所来るまで分からなかったが
I realized for the first time how young I was; I didn't get it until I came here,
此処だけは今も何故 運命のように香る風
but why is it only here that the wind still smells like destiny?
暖かい陽の光がこぼれる 目を閉じればあの日に戻れる
Warm sunlight spills down; if I close my eyes, I can return to that day.
いつしか君の面影は 消えてしまうよ何処かへ
Before I know it, your visage fades away into somewhere unknown.
あの日以来 景色変わらない 散りゆく花びらは語らない
Since that day, the scenery hasn't changed, and the scattering petals say nothing.
さくらの下に響いた 君の声今はもう
Your voice that once echoed under the cherry blossoms is now...
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amidst the fluttering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories
君の声が戻ってくる
and your voice come flooding back.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind that never ceases,
あの頃のままで
just like it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
When you parted your hair dancing in the wind,
淡い香り戻ってくる
that faint scent comes flooding back.
二人約束した
Just like when we made our promise,
あの頃のままで
just like it was back then.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira
そっと僕の肩に
Softly onto my shoulder,
舞い落ちたひとひらの花びら
a single fallen petal lands.
手に取り 目をつむれば
Taking it in my hand and closing my eyes,
君が傍にいる
you are right by my side...
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amidst the fluttering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories
君の声が戻ってくる
and your voice come flooding back.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind that never ceases,
あの頃のままで
just like it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
When you parted your hair dancing in the wind,
淡い香り戻ってくる
that faint scent comes flooding back.
二人約束した
Just like when we made our promise,
あの頃のままで
just like it was back then.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Petals dance and fall, memories come dancing back.
花びら舞い散る
Petals dance and fall...
記憶舞い戻る
...memories come flooding back.
花びら舞い散る
Petals flutter and scatter,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come flooding back.
花びら舞い散る
Petals flutter and scatter,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come flooding back.
花びら舞い散る
Petals flutter and scatter,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come flooding back.
花びら舞い散る
Petals flutter and scatter,
記憶舞い戻る
memories come flooding back.
花びら舞い散る
Petals flutter and scatter.
人はこれって時にどうしても
When people face moments like this, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
they always say, "If only I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, it just can't be helped.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been that way, so it is what it is.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The future ahead is surely deep and uncertain,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but being on our best behavior is boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could hop into a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler...
箱の中の猫を思っても
Even if I think about the cat in the box,
後悔だけが胸を焦がして
only regret scorches my chest,
いつもあの猜疑心が遮るんだわ
and that suspicion always gets in the way.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been that way, so it is what it is.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The future ahead is surely deep and uncertain,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but being on our best behavior is boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could hop into a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler...
どこをどうやってもね
No matter how you slice it,
時間ってのは戻せない
you can't turn back time.
レンズ越し未来にめがけて
Aiming through the lens toward the future,
ピースサイン伝えてる 今のとこいい調子
flashing a peace sign—doing good so far.
青春の1ページも
Even a single page of youth
たったの1ページで
is just one brief page,
自慢の人生のハイライトも
and a proud highlight of life
一夜きりのTweetのbuzzみたい
is like a one-night viral tweet.
君と出会った日のことを覚えてるよ
I still remember the day I met you,
イヤフォン垂らして
with earphones dangling,
この曲をきいていたよ
listening to this song.
あれから数えて今日は何年目！？
Counting from then, what year is today?!
今じゃ足跡 どこも残るから これは歌詞カード
Since footprints linger everywhere now, on this lyric sheet
載せず鍵かけておこう ＃％＆＄！"～
I'll keep it locked up and unposted: #%&$!"~
ほらね、聴き取れない！！
See? You can't make it out!!
皆いつもくよくよ悩み
Everyone always frets and worries,
締め切りに追われ歴史を作り
chasing deadlines and creating history,
弱さを無理やり ごまかし
forcibly glossing over their weaknesses.
君の芝生は緑 青じゃなくていい
Your grass is green; it doesn't have to be greener.
アイドル撮られちゃった真冬の空に
An idol caught on camera under the midwinter sky,
政治家ぶれてブレちゃった帰り道
a politician wavering on the way home,
とうちゃんローン組んだ 見果てぬ先
Dad took out a loan for an endless future,
でも時は全部を流して
yet time washes it all away.
人はこれって時にどうしても
When people face moments like this, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
they always say, "If only I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, it just can't be helped.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been that way, so it is what it is.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The future ahead is surely deep and uncertain,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but being on our best behavior is boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could hop into a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler...
俺ってやつはいつも 気づいた時は手遅れ
A guy like me is always too late by the time I notice,
絵空事ばかり うつつ抜かして
obsessing over nothing but pipe dreams,
大事な人すら救えない
unable to save even someone precious.
だからこんな歌で自分に言い聞かせて
That's why I lecture myself with a song like this.
あの時 あいつは多分 気を使って
Back then, they were probably being considerate,
特に顔色かえず 何もないふり
not changing their expression, pretending nothing was wrong.
なんでいわないんだって ムカついてもね
Even if I got annoyed, wondering why they didn't say anything,
やさしさからきてたなら しょうがないね
if it came from kindness, I guess it can't be helped.
願わくばディスコで 親父と母さんが会った日に行きたいね
If possible, I'd like to go to the day Mom and Dad met at the disco.
後ろのジョックスに酒 かけて息子じきじきにチャンス作ってやるぜ
I'll spill a drink on the jocks behind them and make a chance myself as their son.
どんなでかい時計だってすべてさ
No matter how big the clock is,
始まりはこんな小さい歯車
it all begins with a tiny gear like this.
細かいことはもういいや 疲れた
I'm done with the fine details, I'm tired.
別に怒ってないってさ 未来は
It's not mad at us at all—the future, that is.
人はこれって時にどうしても
When people face moments like this, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
they always say, "If only I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, it just can't be helped.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been that way, so it is what it is.
きっと先は深くて不安定
Surely what lies ahead is deep and uncertain,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but being on our best behavior is no fun.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If we could board the time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become time travelers...
Forever Young
Yo
シボレーのドアを蹴り開けて 街に飛び出した俺達
Kicking open the Chevy's door, we charged out into the city.
暴力 酒に女 音楽 中指立てる大人の仮面にゃ
Violence, booze, women, music—flipping off the masks that adults wear.
Oh さぁ踊ろう 「今日」という日を生き急ぐメンバー
Oh, let's dance! A crew rushing to live out "today."
足りねぇか？ Little louder ! 欲望渦巻く路上が現場
Not enough? Little louder! The streets swirling with desire are our scene!
Yeah いつだってそうだろ ブルハ 尾崎 永ちゃんが教科書
Yeah, it's always been like that—The Blue Hearts, Ozaki, and E-chan were our textbooks.
くたばるまで格好つけてぇ 誓ったよあの放課後
We swore that afternoon after school we'd keep acting cool until we drop!
俺らピーターパン 「またいつか」なんて言っちゃいかん
We're Peter Pan, don't you dare say "maybe someday"!
嘲笑っとる大人に言ってやらぁ 人生はたったの一回だ
Let's tell those sneering adults: you only get one life!
Ah 胸の奥底 初期衝動
Ah, deep within our chest, that primal impulse...
見て見ぬフリ No, no
Pretending not to notice—no, no!
夢追い 笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, laughed at, covered in scars, glaring bright—my way!
Go on! You should know who we are
Forever Young
Hey! Just next to me from now
大切なことは魂の状態
what matters most is the state of your soul!
Forever Young
Hey! It's your turn next time from here
「あの日始めれば良かった」
"I should have started back on that day"—
その次の始めるべき時は今
the next best time to start is right now!
高笑いする都会の喧騒 ウケ狙いならば振り向けれんぞ
The booming laughter of the city's hustle—if you're just playing for cheap laughs, you can't turn heads!
何連呼？ 忘れろ？ 夢流した便所 見下ろしてきやがる摩天楼
Repeating what? Forget it? Skyscrapers looking down on the toilet where dreams were flushed!
Oh まるで勝新みたく破天荒 伝説へとアテンド
Oh, wild and unprecedented just like Katsu Shin, escorted on the way to legend!
怖にゃあ怖にゃあてその程度
If you're scared, then that's all you'll ever amount to.
捨てろ負け惜しみ 過去の栄光
Throw away sore loser excuses and past glories!
永遠なんぞはねぇて いつか天へ召され
There's no such thing as forever—one day we'll be summoned to heaven.
ペンで書き殴ったこの魂は2PACみたく誰かの心を通過
This soul scribbled down with a pen pierces someone's heart just like 2Pac!
なぁ 何か忘れちゃねぇか 人生まるで映画 皆がエンターテイナー
Hey, haven't you forgotten something? Life is like a movie, everyone's an entertainer!
思い出せ 思想は現実化する 誰がHighway飛ばすBentayga
Remember, thoughts materialize into reality! Who's speeding a Bentayga down the highway?
Ah 胸の奥底 初期衝動
Ah, deep within our chest, that primal impulse...
見て見ぬフリ No, no
Pretending not to notice—no, no!
夢追い 笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, laughed at, covered in scars, glaring bright—my way!
Go on! You should know who we are
Forever Young
Hey! 俺達は今日だって
Hey! Even today, we...
若気の至りのような夢を追いかけて来た
...have been chasing after dreams that seemed like youthful folly!
Forever Young
Hey! 変わるはずなんてない
Hey! There's no way we'd ever change!
さぁ 滾ってやろうぜ！
Come on, let's get fired up!
今日は残された人生で 一番若い日だろ
Today is the youngest day of the rest of your life, isn't it?
半端な覚悟ならドブに捨てな (永遠)
If your resolve is half-baked, toss it in the ditch! (Forever)
往生際が悪い テメー笑い飛ばし 誇れBetter days
A sore loser—laugh it off and take pride in better days!
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet! We won't let it end until we burn out! (Forever)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet! We won't let it end until we drop dead! (Forever)
Forever Young
もう夢を追いかけ本気になった心は
A heart that has become truly serious about chasing dreams
自分の指図も受けない
won't even take orders from itself!
Forever Young
Hey! その思いから逃れられないなら
Hey! If you can't escape from that desire,
自ら向かうだけ
then just charge straight toward it yourself!
終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで (永遠)
We won't let it end until we burn out! (Forever)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet! We won't let it end until we drop dead! (Forever)
まだ終わらない
It's not over yet!
Forever Young
そう 今日という日は お前に残された人生の一番若い日
That's right, today is the youngest day of the rest of your life!
イエーイ！
Yay!
マリン来てくれてありがとう！
Marine, thanks for coming!
いや、楽しかった！イエイイエイイエイ！
Man, that was so much fun! Yay, yay, yay!
いや、マジこの「Forever Young」って曲をマリンと一緒に歌いたかったの！
Seriously, I've wanted to sing this song "Forever Young" with Marine so badly!
「Forever Young」って曲をね！
Yeah, the song "Forever Young"!
あー、それはマリンが…
Ah, is that so Marine...
おばさんにならないように？
...doesn't become an old lady?
そう、もうフォーエバーのヤングだから！って言うね！
Exactly! Saying "You're forever young!"
そうだね。永遠にね、ヤング気味で。
That's right. Keeping that youthful feeling forever.
みんな、みんな、Forever Youngだね。
Everyone, everyone is forever young.
みんなヤング！
Everyone is young!
で、マリン…
And Marine...
今日はね、今日ね、
Today, today...
え、後ろ見て？
Hey, look behind us!
演奏してくれた！
They played for us!
気まずいよ
It's awkward!
今日ね、演奏してくれたみんなが...
Everyone who played for us today...
乗ってる、乗ってるよ。
They're grooving, they're into it!
乗ってるでしょ？え、どの子と写真撮りたい？
Right? So, which one do you wanna take a photo with?
え、そんな1人だけみたいな、そんななんか...
Picking just one would feel kind of...
いや、2人選んでいい、2人選んでいい。
No, you can pick two! Pick two!
かわいそうだろ選ばれない奴！
I'd feel bad for the one left out!
2人選ぼう、2人。
Let's pick two, two of them.
これもう、ころねすきーだからさぁ...
But that one's a Koronesuki, so...
いいよ、マリンが選ぶんだよ。
It's fine, you're the one choosing, Marine.
あ、マリンが...
Ah, I choose...
最初は...
The first one is...
待って、映して後ろ。
Wait, show them in the back.
みんな下向いて。
Everyone, look down.
細犬さん。
Thin Dog-san.
かわいい！ / かわいい。
So cute! / Cute.
じゃあ細犬...まず細犬と写真撮ろっか。
Let's take a photo with Thin Dog first.
かわいいよ、細犬。
Thin Dog is so cute.
こっちおいでマリン。 / こっちでいいね。
Come over here, Marine. / Over here, right?
はい、細犬です。えっと、細犬はギターかな？
Here's Thin Dog. Is Thin Dog on guitar?
ギターですか？細犬ちゃん。
Are you on guitar, Thin Dog-chan?
ベロの色が... / かわいいね。
The tongue color is... / Cute, right?
乾いてるベロ。
The tongue is dry.
ベロ乾いちゃっ...死んでるんだけど、ベロの色がね。
The tongue is dry... It's dead, but the tongue color...
あ、これ乾いてる。
Ah, it's definitely dry.
乾いてる。あんま触んないでね。
It's dry. Don't touch it too much.
ごめんね、いっぱい触って。
Sorry for touching you so much.
次誰がいい？あと1人、あと1人。
Who's next? One more, one more!
じゃあ... / 太犬？ / 太犬。
Then... / Fat Dog? / Fat Dog.
太犬だね。
Fat Dog it is.
太犬はドラムです。かわいい！
Fat Dog is on drums. So cute!
太犬！でかい！
Fat Dog! It's huge!
かわいいね。
So cute.
ベロの色がちょっと明るい。
Its tongue color is a bit brighter...
細犬より。
...than Thin Dog's.
撮った？みんな撮った？ / 撮った？
Got the shot? Did everyone take a photo? / Got it?
かわいい！
So cute!
オッケーだね。うん、オッケー。
All good, right? Yep, okay!
え、じゃあ最後さ、2人でも撮ろうよ、2人でも。
Hey, let's take one with just the two of us at the end!
あ、そうだね！2人でも撮ろう、2人でも。
Ah, good idea! Let's take one with just the two of us.
マリン立って。
Marine, stand up.
あ、ごめんごめん！ / やっぱり撮りたいみたいだから...
Ah, sorry, sorry! / It looks like they want one too...
あ、やっぱりね、ころねすきーともね。
Ah, of course, with the Koronesuki too.
撮りますか。ころねすきー、ころさん好き？
Shall we? Koronesuki, do you like Koro-san?
好き？ころさん好き？
Do you? Do you like Koro-san?
あ、よかった。 / え、マリンも好き？
Ah, good! / Do you like Marine too?
間に入ろう。 / なんでだよ！
Let's stand between them. / Why would you do that?!
ころねすきーなのに、ころさんの隣に立てない気分どう？
How does it feel to be a Koronesuki and not be able to stand next to Koro-san?
嬉しい？マリンが隣でいいね？
Happy? Aren't you glad to have Marine next to you?
嬉しくない！？本当は好きなんでしょ？
You're not happy?! You secretly love it, don't you?
やめろ！やめろよ！
Stop it! Cut it out!
だめ、もうだめ、帰るよ。帰るよもう。 / 帰ろう。
No way, I'm heading home. I'm leaving. / Let's go.
はい、今日はね、このバンドメンバーがいましたけれどもですね... / ええ。
Alright, we had our band members here today, but... / Yeah.
え、マリンとも最後撮りたい！ / あ、撮ろう撮ろう。せっかくだね。
I wanna take one last photo with Marine! / Let's do it! Since we're here!
フォーエバーヤングだから、今日は。
Because we're forever young today!
ねえ、マイク！ / マイク！
Hey, the mic! / The mic!
間違えて...色々間違えちゃってるけどさ、マイクね。うん、いいよいいよ。
You've got it all mixed up, but yeah, the mic. It's fine, it's fine!
デカい声で喋れば拾うから。
It'll pick up if I talk loudly anyway.
ね、こうやってね。撮れた？
Yeah, like this. Got it?
いけてる？ / 太犬...
Looking good? / Fat Dog...
中心として...
Centering on it...
笑顔笑顔！撮れたね？ / うん！
Smile, smile! We got it, right? / Yep!
ありがとう、マリン！ / ありがとう！
Thank you, Marine! / Thank you!
ころねちょっと次の曲があるから行くけど... / 次の曲、うん。
I have to get ready for the next song, so I gotta go... / Next song, yeah.
1人で帰れる？ / おー、え、大丈夫、大丈夫大丈夫。
Can you make it back alone? / Oh, yeah, I'll be fine, totally fine!
じゃあ、バンドメンバーのことよろしく。 / え？
Alright, take care of the band members! / Huh?
じゃあ、マリンばいばい！
Bye-bye, Marine!
え？よろしくって何よよろしく...
Huh? What do you mean "take care of them"...
え、どんなムードこれ？あ、え？え？
What kind of mood is this? Wait, huh? Huh?
みんな、あ、そしてみんな、次の曲でーす！
Everyone... and now, everyone, here's the next song!
なぁ なぁ なぁ...
Na na na...
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to depend on others, how to run away, how to make excuses,
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
I've finally learned them, acquired them, a flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to act cool, how to get cocky, how to brace myself, how to age gracefully,
脂乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしない身体
In my prime, cloudy-eyed, with a sloppy body,
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be disliked, how to be adored, how to scold, how to clash gracefully,
もっと覚えたい事が 山のようにある
There's a mountain of things I still want to learn.
のびしろしかないわ
I've got nothing but room to grow.
もうのびしろしかないわ
There's really nothing but room to grow.
俺らまだのびしろしかないわ
We still have nothing but room to grow.
悪者扱い 虐げて来た街で
Treated like villains in the town that oppressed us,
悪者扱い 虐げて来た大人へ
Treated like villains, to the adults who looked down on us,
変わりゆく俺 鏡の中へ
Changing as I am, looking into the mirror,
尋ねても答えなら
even if I ask, the answer is...
去る者は追わない 引くとこ引いて
Never chasing after those who leave, backing off when needed,
丸く収めたり
settling things peacefully,
軽く受け流して
lightly letting things slide,
鏡の中で
in front of the mirror,
泡立てるお前
lathering up shaving cream.
首を括れやしなかった歌
A song that kept me from ending it all,
たったの3文字で
in just three simple words.
日々重くなる足取りで
With footsteps growing heavier by the day,
自分の歩幅で闊歩してる
I'm striding forward at my own pace.
カマすとこカマす
Going hard when it counts,
まかすとこ任す
delegating when I can,
割と適当な段取りで
with reasonably casual planning.
やっと分かって来たかも
Maybe I'm finally getting the hang
このポンコツの操縦の仕方を
of how to handle this piece of junk of mine.
19の時の「ついに来たか…」より
Even more than thinking "It's finally here..." at nineteen,
もっと清々しい気持ち
it's a much more refreshing feeling.
隅田川にかかる
Crossing over Kachidoki Bridge
勝鬨橋を渡る
that spans across the Sumida River,
左手にスカイツリー
Skytree on my left,
右手に東京タワー
Tokyo Tower on my right,
俺はその真ん中
and I'm right in the middle.
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to depend on others, how to run away, how to make excuses,
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
I've finally learned them, acquired them, a flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to look cool, how to get cocky, how to brace myself, how to act my age
脂乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしない身体
In my absolute prime, with murky eyes and an out-of-shape body
幸せの体感速度は 早く 早く なるばかり
The perceived speed of happiness only keeps getting faster and faster
傷が癒えていく速度は 遅く なるばかり
The speed at which wounds heal only keeps getting slower
他人に期待をしないのが 今の俺の強み
Not expecting anything from others is my strength right now
手引いても進める距離なら 行くぜ騙し騙し
If it's a distance I can make by slacking, I'll go, winging it as I go
身の程を知るほどに 胸を張り いつも通り
The more I know my place, the prouder I stand, just as usual
でも時にしたっていーぜ伸び やっと「大人気ない」が出来る歳
But it's fine to stretch out sometimes; I'm finally at the age where I can act immature
小さな枠組み ただの数字 縛られずに でも腹くくり
Not bound by petty frameworks or mere numbers, yet fully resolved
あの日の俺が立ち止まる ほどにデカくそびえ立つ
Towering so high that the old me would stop in his tracks
隅田川にかかる 勝鬨橋を渡る
Spanning the Sumida River, crossing the Kachidoki Bridge
重なるスカイツリー
Overlapping with the Skytree,
東京タワーと真ん中の頼りない背中
Tokyo Tower and this unreliable back right in between them
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to depend on others, how to run away, how to make excuses
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
I've finally learned and acquired them with a flexible mind
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to look cool, how to get cocky, how to brace myself, how to act my age
脂乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしない身体
In my absolute prime, with murky eyes and an out-of-shape body
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be disliked, how to be adored, how to scold, how to clash gracefully
覚えた事が山のようにある のびしろしかないわ
There's a mountain of things I've learned; I've got nothing but room to grow
のびしろしかないわ
Nothing but room to grow
俺らまだ のびしろしかないわ
We've still got nothing but room to grow!
くだんない話と
Talks of nonsense
うざったい貴様と
and you annoying bastard,
なみなみの日々に注がれてく
pouring into days brimming to the edge,
怠いが溢れ出していく
laziness overflows.
飯がまだ届かない
The meal still hasn't arrived,
仕事は片付かない
work won't get finished,
うだつの上がらない 毎日にため息ばかり
with nothing going right, every day is full of sighs.
でまたド派手にすっころび
Then falling flat on my face again so dramatically,
洗い立てのシャツにこぼすコーヒー
spilling coffee on a freshly washed shirt.
前のめりその姿勢だけは褒めて良し
At least praise me for that forward-leaning posture!
肩落とす並木通り 増えた柄と差し色に
Drooping shoulders down the tree-lined street, with new stains as accent colors,
嗚呼…本当嫌んなる毎日だ
Ah... every single day is truly so exasperating!
やりたくないことやったって
Even if we do things we don't want to do,
嫌々早起きしたって
even if we wake up early against our will,
その分素敵な何かが 訪れるとかそんなわけでもないのにさ
it's not like anything wonderful will come our way in return.
今日もまた頑張っちゃうよな がむしゃら以外知らないから
Yet here we are doing our best again today, 'cause we don't know any other way than going all out.
不器用で意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
Clumsy and stubborn, may good fortune shine upon us foolishly earnest fools!
重くなってきた荷物をちょっと置いて立ち止まり
Putting down the heavy luggage for a bit to pause,
昨日の事なんざ忘れちまえば同じ
it's all the same once you forget about yesterday.
浴びるday light 羽根伸ばし
Bask in the daylight, spread your wings,
それか月夜にこっそりと吐き出してしまえば良い
or just secretly spit it all out into the moonlight.
でもその前にアレとコレの話
But before that, we have this and that to talk about,
その為には先ずはソレを片し
and to do that, we gotta clean that up first.
って今は何時？ いやその前に
Wait, what time is it now? No, before that,
今日もなんだかんだ騒がしい毎度あり
it's noisy today as always, thanks for having us!
1ヶ月くらい何にも 考えずだらだらしていたいな
For about a month, I just wanna laze around without thinking about anything.
ゆっくり休んで遊んで眠っていたいな
I just wanna rest up, play, and sleep...
って思う日もあるけれど
There are days I feel like that, but...
やっとここまでできたんだよ
We've finally made it this far!
ここじゃ終われないんだよ
We can't let it end here!
辛いきついもいつかは 笑い話にできると信じてるんだほら
See, I believe that all the hardships and pain will turn into a laughing matter someday!
今日もまた頑張っちゃうからさ
That's why I'll keep doing my best today too,
がむしゃらに愛を歌うからさ
singing of love with all my might!
目一杯吸い込んだ空気
Breathing in air at the top of my lungs!
嗚呼 本当素晴らしい毎日だ
Ah, every single day is truly wonderful!
やりたくないことやったって
Even if we do things we don't want to do,
嫌々早起きしたって
even if we wake up early against our will,
ほんの少しの幸せに 触れるだけで全部全部ありに思えるんだ
just touching a tiny bit of happiness makes everything feel completely worth it.
明日もまた頑張ってみようか
Shall we try our best again tomorrow?
がむしゃらに生きていくんだ
We're gonna keep living passionately!
不器用で意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
Clumsy and stubborn, may good fortune shine upon us foolishly earnest fools!
do my thing do your thing 肩の力を抜いて柔軟に
Do my thing, do your thing, relax your shoulders and stay flexible
again do my thing do your thing あと1ミリ背伸び
Again, do my thing, do your thing, stretch just one more millimeter!
ああ 本当嫌んなっちゃうよな それでも今を生きている
Ah, it really gets so exasperating, but even so, we're living in the present.
不器用で意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目なあなたに幸あれ
Clumsy and stubborn, may good fortune shine upon you, foolishly earnest soul!
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonably priced quality plus a see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても 底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
Even if you struggle wanting to become like them, you'll sink like into a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonably priced quality plus a see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて 君の心に落とすimagination
NickelBurn and ignite, dropping imagination into your heart.
ギリギリでフライできず地獄送りさ 君が飛べなかった理由を一つ教えたろうか
Barely unable to fly, sent straight to hell; shall I tell you one reason why you couldn't take off?
それは目の前のプロップスに心揺らぎ近道した結果 誰かの後をつけてるだけだったからさ
It's because swayed by the props before you, you took a shortcut, ending up just following someone else's tracks.
未だわからないか最初は気づいてた 知らぬふりして自分の道だと言い聞かせた
Still don't get it? Though you noticed at first, you feigned ignorance, convincing yourself it was your own path.
他は騙せないオリジナルを奏でないと 過去の自分に足を引っ張られて退場
You can't fool others unless you play something original; dragged down by your past self, you exit the stage.
俺とお前との差は遺伝子レベル 俺を狂わせた父母祖父母には感謝してる
The difference between you and me is on a genetic level; I'm grateful to my parents and grandparents who drove me crazy.
さらに磨き上げた自分自身にも感謝してる
And I'm grateful to myself for polishing it further.
なのに軟化してる君 差が離れてくうちに 絶望を感じどうせラップやめるよ
Yet you soften up as the gap widens; feeling despair, you'll probably quit rapping anyway.
5年後？いや4年後？これは余命宣告
In 5 years? No, 4 years? This is your terminal prognosis.
現状に満足して威張ってんの？
Are you satisfied with the status quo and acting all haughty?
俺ら発展途上でもかっけえぞ
We're still developing, but we're still damn cool!
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonably priced quality plus a see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても 底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
Even if you struggle wanting to become like them, you'll sink like into a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonably priced quality plus a see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて 君の心に落とすimagination
NickelBurn and ignite, dropping imagination into your heart.
恋焦がれた男達と時をかけた女達 上辺だけのお友達がお前の事甘やかす
Yearning men and women who leaped through time, surface-level friends coddle you.
命削りのらりくらり情熱だけを注ぐ歌詞 現実に頬濡らし 理想達が雨降らす
Whittling away life, drifting along, lyrics pouring only passion; soaking cheeks with reality, ideals make it rain.
あれもカスでこれもカスで俺の歌詞で振り向かす 狂気になって無視したって知らぬうちに街を這う
That's trash and this is trash, turning heads with my lyrics; even if you go mad and ignore it, it crawls through the streets before you know it.
体揺らし声を枯らしたって誰も聞いてない 導かれて聴いてみても耳は糸を引いてない
Even if you shake your body and rasp your voice, nobody's listening; even if guided to listen, ears aren't hooked.
今日と明日明後日も白紙の中漁ってる 思想すらも曲がってるだけど顔は笑ってる
Today, tomorrow, and the day after, rummaging through blank sheets; even thoughts are twisted, but smiling on the outside.
嘘だらけの肥溜めで逆上せるまで浸かって 空に祈り捧げたって変えれるのは声だけ
Soaking in a cesspool of lies until flushed; even if praying to the sky, the only thing that can change is the voice.
何かあれば孤独気取り毟り取る金 指で擦りめくり表あれば裏探すだけ
If anything happens, acting lonely while snatching up cash; rubbing and flipping fingers, if there's a front, just seeking the back.
歯止め利かぬ無駄な愚痴も全て愛で砕けてる もうこんな歌詞は書きたくない 全部お前のせい
Unstoppable, useless grumbles all shattered by love; I don't want to write lyrics like this anymore—it's all your fault!
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonably priced quality plus a see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても 底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
Even if you struggle wanting to become like them, you'll sink like into a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonably priced quality plus a see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて 君の心に落とすimagination
NickelBurn and ignite, dropping imagination into your heart.
チ・チ・チ・チーム友達
T-T-T-Team Tomodachi
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？ え？ チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi!
関西 関東 西 東
Kansai, Kanto, West, East
北 南 チーム
North, South, Team
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？ え？ チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi!
お好み焼き 食う鶴橋
Eating okonomiyaki in Tsuruhashi
腹いっぱい 飯は美味い
Belly full, food is delicious
一人じゃ寂しいし 電話切った後
Being alone is lonely, and after hanging up,
かけ直した後 すぐ行く会いに
After calling back, heading right over to meet up
T-E-A-M T-O-M-O-D-A-C-H-I
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 混ざり合い
Team Tomodachi, mixing together
契り交わし 飲んでる酒
Pledging vows, drinking sake
契り 契り
Pledge, pledge
契ろう 契ろう
Let's pledge, let's pledge
契り 契り
Pledge, pledge
契ろう 契ろう
Let's pledge, let's pledge
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？ え？ チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi!
関西 関東 西 東
Kansai, Kanto, West, East
北 南 チーム
North, South, Team
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friends, Team Friends
俺たち何？ え？ チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Friends!
チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friends, Team Friends, Team Friends
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friends, Team Friends
エーーイ！
Yeah!
Yo, Yo, Yo, 勝手にしてね、Yo!
Yo, Yo, Yo, do as you please, Yo!
見ーてんのか？ 見てんのか、Yo!
Are you watching? Are you watching, Yo!
オイ、声が悪いんじゃ、Yo!
Hey, our voices sound terrible, Yo!
ちょっとあの... ちょっとね、ちょっとね
Wait, uh... A bit, yeah, a bit.
この帽子とかのせいでね、ちょっとヤカラっぽくなっちゃうけどね
With these caps and all, we kinda look like thugs, though.
うん、かっこいいじゃん！ こんな格好いつかしてみたかったんだよ〜
Yeah, but it looks cool! I've always wanted to dress like this sometime!
てかマジこれバチクソ高いからこれ気をつけてね
Seriously though, this stuff is crazy expensive, so be careful.
え、本当にね、今日来たら「これ用意してあるんで」って言われて、「え、これ何これ！？」って
Really, when I arrived today, they told me, "We have this ready for you," and I was like, "Eh? What's this?!"
重たいでしょ？
Heavy, right?
うん、重たい！ でもかっこいい！
Yeah, heavy! But cool!
あの、ロック・リーみたいになってるから今、ウチら
Like, we're basically Rock Lee right now.
ロック・リーｗ
Rock Lee, lol.
重りつけてるからね、今
We're wearing weights right now.
解き放たれたらもっと動けるからね
Once we're unleashed, we can move way faster.
そう、外したらね、いい感じになりますけど
Right, once we take them off, we'll be in top form.
え、でも、ころねさん、周年おめでとうございます！
But anyway, Korone-san, happy anniversary!
え、ありがとう！
Eh, thank you!
もう7周年だよ、ころね
It's already the 7th anniversary, Korone.
ねー！ すごい！ 早いよね
Right?! Amazing! Time flies.
え、待ってみこちゃんの衣装見て？ これ誕生日で見たやつね！
Wait, look at Miko-chan's outfit! This is the one from your birthday, right!
かわいい！ え、後ろも見せて、後ろも！
Cute! Show us the back too, the back!
ちょっと今回用意してくれたこの装飾になんかマッチしてて草なんですけど
It kind of matches the accessories prepared for this, which is hilarious, but...
めっちゃマッチしてます！
It matches super well!
でもそれで言うとさ、ころね、この衣装さ、ゲーマーズのイベントのやつじゃない？
Speaking of which, Korone, isn't that outfit from the Gamers event?
そうそう！「超超超超ゲーマーズ」の衣装！
Yeah yeah! The "Cho Cho Cho Cho Gamers" outfit!
かわいいじゃん！
It's so cute!
みこちゃん、今日ね、これが初お披露目なんだ、この衣装の
Miko-chan, today is actually the debut of this outfit!
え！？ これで！？ この「チーム友達」で初お披露目になっちゃったんですけど！
What?! With this?! It ended up debuting with "Team Friends"?!
いいじゃん、いいじゃん！ かわいい！ ちょっと短くない？
It's great, it's great! Cute! Isn't it a bit short?
え、そうなの。ちょっとエッチじゃない？ これめっちゃ短いんだよね、大丈夫？
Yeah, isn't it kind of sexy? It's really short. Is it okay?
あ、まだ見えてない。コラッ！ 見せるなよ！ 大丈夫かな...
Ah, nothing's showing yet. Hey! Don't flash people! I wonder if it's okay...
え、しかもね、ころねなんかさ、めっちゃ胸がパツパツって言われてて、これ
And also, people keep telling Korone that the chest is super tight in this.
いや、なんかちょっとシワができちゃってるの、パツパツで。弾け飛びそうだよ、なんかｗ
Yeah, there are wrinkles forming from how tight it is. Feels like it's about to burst open, lol.
多分ね、サイズが合ってないんだと思う
I think the size probably doesn't fit right.
あー、でもそのぐらいがね、いいですからね
Ah, but that tight fit is great!
え、じゃ写真撮ろうよ、写真！
Hey, let's take a photo, a photo!
え、写真撮りたい！ ちょっとアップ目で撮りたいんだよな
Yeah, I want to take one! I want to take a close-up shot.
いいね。しゃがもうよ。しゃがむかい？
Nice. Let's crouch down. Shall we crouch?
Yo, Yo! あ、いいじゃん！
Yo, Yo! Ah, looking good!
Yo, Yo. スパイダーマンみたいになっちゃったｗ
Yo, Yo. I ended up looking like Spider-Man, lol.
Yo, Yo! え、じゃサングラスもさ、取ってさ、やろうよ
Yo, Yo! Hey, let's take off our sunglasses too and do it.
せっかくだからね。よいしょ、よいしょ。ちょっと待ってね、みんなね
Since we have the chance. Alright, alright. Wait a moment, everyone.
行くよー！ せーの！ はい！
Here we go! Ready, set, cheese!
あ、いい！ 撮れた撮れた！
Ah, nice! We got it, we got it!
え、アップ目で撮る？ アップ目で撮りたい！ イェーイ！
Want to take a close-up? I want to take a close-up! Yay!
カメラをね、いただきましてね。あ、どう？
Bringing the camera closer... How's this?
イェーイ！ Yo! これ出てる？
Yay! Yo! Is this on screen?
チーム友達 チーム友達 チーム友達...
Team Friends, Team Friends, Team Friends...
ど、どこ歌ってんの？ｗ
Wh-what part are you singing? lol
え、でもさ、この曲さ、選んでくれたの嬉しかったよ
But you know, I was really happy you chose this song.
やっぱ「チーム友達」っていうぐらいの歌だから、友達と歌いたくて
It's called "Team Friends" after all, so I wanted to sing it with a friend.
だから誰でも良かったんだけど別に、友達だからみんな
So really, anyone would've done, since everyone is my friend.
おい！
Hey!
嘘嘘！ｗ 特に！ 特にみこみこと歌いたかった！
Just kidding! lol Especially! I especially wanted to sing with Mikomiko!
ありがとう来てくれて。チーム友達だから当たり前じゃん！
Thanks for coming. Of course, since we're Team Friends!
チーム友達〜！ イェーイ！
Team Friends! Yay!
え、でもそろそろ次の曲なんじゃないですか？
But isn't it about time for the next song?
あ、そう、もうちょっとね、もうちょっとだけ続くんじゃよなんだけど
Ah, right, it's like "it's gonna continue just a little bit longer," but...
うん、次どんな感じなの？
Yeah, what's next like?
え、次はね、パンツですね
Next is... pants.
え？ パンツ？ パンツ？
Eh? Pants? Pants?
恥ずかしいｗ やめて！ 撮らないで！
That's embarrassing lol. Stop! Don't film that!
パンツって、この履いてるパンツってこと？
By pants, you mean the underwear we're wearing?
え、みこさん履いてないの？ みこさん履いてないの、パンツ？
Eh, Miko-san, aren't you wearing any? Miko-san, aren't you wearing underwear?
安心してください、履いてますよ
Don't worry, I'm wearing them.
履いてる？ あ、よかった、じゃあ
You are? Ah, good then.
え、ころねはまだこれからなんだよね、パンツ
For Korone, the pants are just about to begin.
え？ 履いてないってこと！？
Eh? Does that mean you're not wearing any?!
ころねはちょっとこれからなの。だからごめん、みこみこ、これからだから、ころねパンツ
It's starting now for Korone. So sorry, Mikomiko, pants are just beginning for Korone.
え、パ、パンツ？ パンツ？
Eh, pa-pants? Pants?
3 2 1... Yo!
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, be naked
But wearing PANTS!
Animal, naked! Nature, naked! People, naked!
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, be naked
But wearing PANTS!
No punch, no fight, no punch, no steal, no punch, no knife
Kick it, naked, kick it, naked, naked King! (Ho!)
Kicking Naked King Naked King Naked King
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, be naked
but wearing pants!
Animal naked, nature naked, people naked, but wearing pants!
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, be naked
but wearing pants!
You say naked, I say no! I say naked, you say no!
You are wearing, I say pants! I say wearing, you say pants!
Kicking Naked King Naked King
Kicking Naked Kicking Naked King Naked King
Sidewalk, push! Sidewalk, push!
I'm wearing pants! But I can pose naked!
Ah listen up
キラっと光る犬歯がお似合いの口が物語る
The mouth suited with glistening fangs tells a tale
リリカるがもくもくと充満し織り成すスモーキーなストーリー
As the lyrical fills the air thick and smoky, weaving a smoky story
Let me see
不確かな平穏と確かな不安を纏い彷徨う
Wandering cloaked in uncertain peace and certain anxiety
お揃いじゃないことに恐れ慄く
Terrified of not matching everyone else
十色の価値観 騒ぐラジカル 何がはじまる？
Ten colors of values, radical unrest, what is about to begin?
不器用な生き様に心痛む (Ahh)
My heart aches for such a clumsy way of living (Ahh)
I wonder why 理性を欠いたサバイブ
I wonder why, a survival devoid of reason
願っても願ってもなくならない
No matter how much I wish, it won't go away
I wonder why 危険度ハイなマイライフ
I wonder why, my high-risk life
Do it again どこまで
Do it again, how far will it go?
Chase chase, Where is my utopia こじ開ける扉
Chase, chase, where is my utopia? Prying open the door
Viva 現状打破なら飛び乗りな
Viva! If it's to break the status quo, jump on board
くしゃくしゃの紙屑に傷ついたハート重ねる
Piling a wounded heart onto crumpled scrap paper
しわついたまま時を刻む (踊れ)
Ticking away time while still wrinkled (Dance)
数多のお目目から逃げた Back in the day
Fleeing from countless watchful eyes back in the day
ひた隠している ファンキーなヘッド
Constantly hiding this funky head
個性の延長線上にあるギフトも誰かにとってはバグみたい
Even a gift born from individuality seems like a glitch to someone else
伏し目を逸らし 行く当てもない
Looking away with downcast eyes, nowhere to go
現状 感情 洗浄 出来ず立ち往生
Stranded, unable to cleanse current feelings and conditions
抱いても泣いても足掻いても Fall...
Whether embracing, crying, or struggling, fall...
Uhhh 放浪 噛み締め 揺蕩う
Uhhh, wandering, enduring, drifting along
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一歩前に踏み出す アニマル (aww)
An animal taking a step forward (aww)
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に
Acting like a big shot, way ahead, way ahead
(Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww
Critical Critical Criti Criti Criti
Don't panic, Go too far far far
暗闇が Take over さながら予定調和
Darkness takes over, just as predictably planned
覚えたての絶望にほだされ見る見る間に裏目を出す
Swayed by newly learned despair, backfiring in the blink of an eye
手招く反逆のアイコン 一抹の不安抱くも邂逅
Beckoning icon of rebellion, meeting despite a sliver of anxiety
平和ボケした連中を尻目に日陰練り歩けば Dope Dope Dope
Glancing at the peace-dulled crowd while prowling the shadows, dope, dope, dope
What a uhmmm
山積みトラブルに追われ多忙 やさぐれ罵倒にはなむけ発砲 (BANG!)
Busy chased by piles of trouble; firing a parting shot at sullen curses (BANG!)
Bang ba bang ba bang bang ぶち抜く条理 ヘッドばんばん
Bang ba-bang ba-bang bang, blasting through reason, head banging
出る杭打つのに必死なプライド 塗れの敵に見舞う超ヤバいもん
Dealing something deadly to foes soaked in pride, desperate to strike the nail that sticks out
狂った情緒で冷え切った体温上げるこのエナジーは文字通りザイオン
Raising the chilled body temp of frenzied emotions, this energy is literally Zion
運命捻じ曲げるトリガー 着火する煙たい Dogs のお通りだ (Goooo!)
A trigger that twists fate, igniting smoky Dogs making way (Goooo!)
皆誰もがスペシャルな存在ってこと忘れた結果
The result of everyone forgetting that they are special beings
自分と違う箇所否定して突っぱねる それこそ欠陥
Denying and rejecting what's different from oneself—now that's the real flaw
たくさんの矛盾と向き合い続けて尚 一向になくならない愚かなる (Battle)
Even after constantly facing countless contradictions, this foolish (Battle) never ends
悲愴 失踪 闘争 Never never end
Sorrow, disappearance, conflict, never, never end
散らばる Hollow
Scattered hollows
ぎらり剥き出しの牙と思惑が絡み合う
Glistening bared fangs and hidden motives intertwine
消灯 深い夜と歌う
Lights out, singing with the deep night
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一歩前に踏み出す アニマル (aww)
An animal taking a step forward (aww)
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に
Acting like a big shot, way ahead, way ahead
(Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww
Critical Critical Criti Criti Criti
Don't panic, Go too far far far
Work like a dog 只管に磨いたジョブ
Work like a dog, a craft honed with single-minded devotion
ぼんやり未来が望遠鏡に浮かんだ今日
Today, a faint future appeared in the telescope
いつかのオメルタもスーベニア
Even that past omertà is now a souvenir
凍り付いた心を溶かす My whereabouts
Melting my frozen heart, my whereabouts
マフィオーザ 祝砲を放つ (Yeah)
Mafiosa, firing a celebratory salute (Yeah)
アイネ・クライネ・ナハトムジーク ぐずついた顔はグッバイ
Eine kleine Nachtmusik, goodbye to sullen faces
マフィオーザ 祝福の歌 (Yeah)
Mafiosa, a song of blessing (Yeah)
ようやく見つけた 掛け替えのない居場所
Finally found it, an irreplaceable place to belong
Say hoo! ほら一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Come on, let's dance together
Say hoo! また一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together again
Say hoo! ずっと一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together forever
ようやく気付けた ふたつとない居場所
Finally realized it, a one-of-a-kind place to belong
みんなー！
Everyone!
マフィオーザライブ初お披露目、どうだったー？
How was the first live performance of "Mafiosa"?
ちょっと、PUNCHとマフィオーザで2曲続けてだったんですけど
We did "PUNCH" and "Mafiosa" back-to-back,
こーね、PUNCHっていう曲めちゃめちゃ好きで
and Korone really loves the song "PUNCH",
あのずっと暇の時めちゃめちゃ聴いてたので、
I used to listen to it all the time in my free time,
今回歌えて嬉しいのと、
so I was super happy to sing it today,
コロネスキーにね、ピンクのパンツを履いて踊ってもらえたのがすごく楽しかったので、
and having the Koronesukis wear pink boxer shorts and dance along was so much fun,
みんな踊ってくれてありがとー！
so thank you so much to everyone who danced along!
はい。でね、今回
Alright. And so, this time,
えーと、マフィオーザのライブ初お披露目をしたくて、
um, I really wanted to do the live debut of "Mafiosa",
全部ね、ラップ曲でまとめてみたんですけど、
and put together a full setlist of rap songs...
どうだったかなー？
How was it?
ちょっと初めての試みだったから、
It was my first time trying something like this,
すごいね、あの、準備段階から今日に至るまでめっちゃドキドキで、
so from preparations up until today, my heart was racing,
なんかみんな楽しんでくれるかなー？とか思ってたんだけど、
wondering if everyone would enjoy it.
だからね、みんなが楽しんでノリノリになってくれてたら嬉しいなーと思います。
So I hope you all had fun and were vibing along!
でね、原曲知らないよーっていう方がね、え、結構いると思うんですけど、結構いないか、いると思うんですけど、
And I think there might be quite a few people who don't know the original songs—or maybe not many, but if there are,
もしね、そういう方は是非、めちゃめちゃかっこいいので全部の曲、原曲是非聴いてみてください！
they're all super cool, so please definitely check out the original songs!
あ、最後に歌ったマフィオーザもですね、めちゃめちゃ原曲かっこいいので、
Ah, the original version of "Mafiosa" that I sang at the end is super cool too,
是非みんな聴いてねー！
so please give it a listen, everyone!
はい！ということで、今回もあります！周年グッズです！こちらー！
Alright! With that said, we have anniversary merchandise this year too! Here it is!
急に来る。はい。
That popped up fast. Yes!
え、今回はですね、なんと！うすた京介先生に描き下ろしていただきましたー！ありがとうございます！
And this time, wow! Kyosuke Usuta-sensei drew the illustrations for us! Thank you so much!
1つずつ見ていきますかね。
Let's take a look at each item.
えー最初ですね、YB-2、久しぶりに出ました。
First up, YB-2 makes a return after a while!
え、うちのブランドYB-2です。
Yes, my brand YB-2.
YB-2の、えー、うすた先生バージョンのね、パーカーですー！
It's the YB-2 hoodie, Usuta-sensei version!
えー裏面に、えーイラストが来る感じですね。
The illustration is on the back.
で、胸元に「YB-2」って入ってて、
And "YB-2" is on the chest,
腕にね、あの、ころねのモチーフの骨が入っております。
with Korone's signature bone motif on the sleeves!
これめちゃめちゃかっこいいと思うのでね、お楽しみにー！
I think this looks super cool, so look forward to it!
はい、続いてこちらー！
Alright, next up is this!
こちらですね、あの、パーカーと同じイラストのサコッシュです！
This is a sacoche featuring the same illustration as the hoodie!
結構ね、なんかエキスポとかフェスとか、なんかみんなのね、イベントとかに来る時にサコッシュ使ってる人結構いたなと思って、
I noticed a lot of people using sacoches when coming to events like EXPO or Fes,
こーねもサコッシュ出したい！ということでサコッシュも出しましたー！みんな是非使ってください！
so Korone wanted to make one too, and here it is! Please be sure to use it!
続いてこちらー！
Next up is this!
こちらですね、ごめんなさいね。
Here we have... excuse me.
え、RAP DOG キャップ！
The "RAP DOG Cap"!
こちらをですね、え、ヒコサン先生のデザインで、あの、出させていただきました！ありがとうございます！
This was designed by Hikosan-sensei! Thank you so much!
えーここにね、ころねの骨がクロスしてて、横にまたこれ「YB-2」です。
Here, Korone's bones are crossed, and on the side is "YB-2" again.
これもYB-2なのでね、サコッシュと...あ、サコッシュ、あ、サコッシュもYB-2か！
This is also YB-2, so along with the sacoche... ah, wait, the sacoche is YB-2 as well!
パーカーとサコッシュと帽子、え、全部YB-2のブランドでございます！よろしくお願いします！
The hoodie, sacoche, and cap are all part of the YB-2 brand! Please check them out!
はい、次！
Alright, next!
これはYB-2じゃないころねのランダムラバーストラップ！
This is the "Not-YB-2 Korone Random Rubber Strap"!
こちらね、フカヒレママに描き下ろしてもらいました！ママありがとー！
These were specially drawn by Fukahire-mama! Thank you, Mama!
こちらね、4種類ランダムで。
There are 4 random designs.
で、今回ね、ラップの曲が多かったということで、あのラップをしてるね、ころねのイラストもありますので、
And since there were a lot of rap songs this time, there's an illustration of Korone rapping too,
是非皆さん全種類目指してよかったら買ってみてください！
so please try to collect all four designs if you'd like!
通常衣装と、え、YB-2のジャンプスーツと、ドッグ...え、GOOD DOG衣装と、
There's the default outfit, the YB-2 jumpsuit, Dog... er, GOOD DOG outfit,
え、ラッパー衣装ですね。よかったら、はい、こちらもご検討くださーい！
and the rapper outfit! Please consider getting these too!
そしてフルセットの購入特典は、えー、うすた先生描き下ろしのですね、ポストカード！
And the bonus for purchasing the full set is a postcard drawn by Usuta-sensei!
え、数量限定版もありますけれども、めちゃめちゃ、あの、用意しておりますので、
There is a limited quantity version too, but we've prepared plenty of them,
あの、急がないで大丈夫です。あの、マジで結構用意したので、あの、ゆっくりご購入くださーい！
so no need to rush. Seriously, we prepared a ton, so take your time purchasing!
はい。で、通常バージョンはね、箔押しの複製サイン入りとなっております。
Yes! And the standard version comes with a foil-stamped duplicate signature.
はい！ということで、今回のライブもみんな、たくさん見てくれてありがとうございましたー！
Alright! So, thank you all so much for watching today's live show!
以上、「LAZY DOG NIGHT!」でしたー！みんな本当いつもありがとねー！
That was "LAZY DOG NIGHT!" Thank you so much, as always!
また会おう！
Let's meet again!
またねー！
See you!